Guide to the Waltraude Woods, Senior Architect/Planner, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Waltraude Woods, senior architect/planner, Yale University, records
1930-2004
RU 964
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
89
The records consist of studies, reports, surveys, charts, and other materials documenting the activities and projects of Waltraude (Val) Woods as senior architect/planner, Office of Facilities, Yale University.
Yale University. Office of Facilities
Woods, Waltraude
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 46-A (YRG 46-A), Records and materials broadly documenting Yale buildings, facilities, and grounds.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were transferred from the Office of Facilities, 2004.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged in eight series. I. Planning Process, 1953-2004. II. Planning Studies, 1930-2002. III. Planning Projects - Residential, 1990-2001. IV. Arts Area Planning Study, 1951-2000. V. Old Campus, 1994-1996. VI. Framework for Campus Planning Study, 1975-1998. VII. Planning Projects, circa 1968-2001. VIII. Planning Data, 1933-2001 and subsequent accession.
Scope and Contents
When work begins there is usually an area planning study which involves compilation of research material and subsequent investigation, culminating in reports. This is followed by the facility construction projects related to the initial study. These involve a completion of such documents as reference material, project scope description, project authorizations, consultant selection, meeting notes, memoranda, reports, sketches, plans, specification, and estimates.
Campus planning; College buildings -- Design and construction; College buildings -- Maintenance and repair; Yale University -- Buildings; Yale University. Office of Facilities
- Planning process, 1953-2004; Series I
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2040
  - Chronological files
    - 1953-1955 (Box 1)
    - 1953-1973 (Box 2)
    - 1960-1979 (Box 3)
    - 1980-1989 (Box 4)
    - 1990-1999 (Box 5)
    - 1994 - summary (Box 6)
    - 1974-2004 (Box 7)
    - 2000-2004 (Box 7a)
  - Commissions and estimating (COMMIS/EST)
    - 1995-2001 (Box 8)
    - 2002-2004 (Box 9)
- Planning studies, 1930-2002; Series II
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2038
  - Diverse (DIVERS)
    - 1968-1989 (Box 10)
    - 1990-1991 (Box 11)
    - 1992-1994 (Box 12)
    - 1995 (Box 13)
    - 1996-2000 (Box 14)
  - Campus Improvements (CAMP. IMPROV)
  - Classrooms (CLASSRM)
    - 1967-1987 (Box 15)
    - 1988-1989 (Box 16)
    - 1990-1997 (Box 17)
  - Lighting (LIGHT)
    - 1989-1990 (Box 18)
    - 1988-2003 - Surveys (Box 19)
  - Landscape and Projects (LAND+PROJ), 1987-1990 (Box 20)
  - Signs (SIGNS), 1989-1990 (Box 21)
  - Science Hill (SCIENCE), 1959-1995 (Box 22)
  - Library Shelving Facility (LSF), 1985-1995 (Box 23)
  - 155 Whitney Avenue (155 WHIT), 1996 (Box 24)
  - School of Management (SOM), 1974-1997 (Box 25)
  - Residential (RES)
    - 1930-1979 (Box 26)
    - 1980-1989 (Box 27)
    - 1990-2002 (Box 28)
  - Undergraduate Residential Facilities Planning Study (URFPS)
    - 1990-1994 - 12 Colleges Research (Box 29)
    - 1994 - Research (Box 30)
    - 1994 - Old Campus (Box 31)
    - 1994 (Box 32)
    - 1994-1995 (Box 33)
    - 1995 - Summary Reports (Box 34)
    - 1995 - 12 Colleges (Box 35)
    - 1995-1996 (Box 36)
    - 1996 - 4 Colleges estimates (Box 37)
  - Residential College Renovation (RCR)
    - 1993-1996 (Box 38)
    - 1996 (Box 39)
    - Windows, 1995-1996 (Box 40)
  - Old Campus Residential (OC), 1994-1995 (Box 41)
- Planning projects - residential, 1990-2001; Series III
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2037
  - New Residence Hall Project (NEW RES), 1996-1998 (Box 42)
  - Berkeley College (BK)
    - 1996-1997 (Box 43)
    - 1996-1999 (Box 44)
  - Branford College/Saybrook College Renovations (BR/SY)
    - 1990-1996 - Research (Box 45)
    - 1994-1996 - Branford research (Box 46)
    - 1996-1997 (Box 47)
    - 1998-1999 (Box 48)
  - Timothy Dwight College Renovation (TD)
    - 1990-1996 - Research (Box 49)
    - 1996-1999 (Box 50)
    - 2000-2001 (Box 51)
- Arts area planning study, 1951-2000; Series IV
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2036
  - Arts Area Planning Study - Arts Area, Phase II Comprehensive Programming and Planning Study (ARTS)
    - 1990-1995 - Research (Box 52)
    - 1994-1995 (Box 53)
    - 1995-1996 (Box 54)
  - Finance (Box 55)
  - Yale University Art Gallery Programming - Yale University Art Gallery/Street Hall Comprehensive Renovation Study (YUAG)
    - 1982-1997 - Reference (Box 56)
    - 1997-1998 (Box 57)
    - 1998-1999 (Box 58)
    - 1999-2000 (Box 58a)
    - 2000 (Box 59)
  - YUAG financial (Box 59a)
  - 1156 Chapel Street Project (1156 CHAP)
  - Reference (REF), 1986-1996 (Box 60)
  - Specifications (SPECS), 1951-1998 (Box 61)
    - 1996-1997 (Box 61a)
    - 1997 (Box 62)
    - 1997 (Box 63)
    - 1998-2001 (Box 64)
    - 1998 - Specifications (Box 65)
- Old campus, 1994-1996; Series V
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2032
  - Linsly Chittenden Hall/Old Campus - Non-Residential (LC/OC) Project
    - 1994-1995 (Box 66)
    - 1995 (Box 67)
    - 1996 (Box 68)
- Framework for campus planning study, 1975-1998; Series VI
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2034
  - Planning (FRAMEWORK)
    - 1975-1994 - Research (Box 69)
    - 1995 (Box 70)
    - 1996 (Box 71)
    - 1997-1998 (Box 72)
- Planning projects, circa 1968-2001; Series VII
  - Projects/Divers
    - A-C (Box 73)
    - D-R (Box 74)
    - S-V (Box 75)
    - W-Z (Box 76)
- Planning data, 1933-2001; Series VIII
  - Assignment Plans, Capital Projects, Space Inventory System (ASSIGN PLANS, CAP PROJECTS, SIS)
    - 1933-1987 (Box 77)
    - 1988-1991 (Box 78)
    - 1992-1993 (Box 79)
    - 1994-1995 (Box 80)
    - 1996-1999 (Box 81)
    - 2000-2004 (Box 82)
  - Historic Preservation (HIST PRES) (Box 83)
  - Parking and Zoning (PARK+ZON), 1964-1999 (Box 84)
  - Taxes and Untaxed Properties (TAX PROP), 1967-1994 (Box 85)
- Records of the University Planning Dept. as maintained by Val Woods, circa 1985-1995; Accession 2003-A-023
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2031
  - Records, circa 1985-1995 (Box 1)
  - Records, circa 1985-1995 (Box 2)